Final level 1 has a format string vulnerability that can be exploited remotely.
在过去的几段视频中，我们学习了如何通过TCP网络与这些程序通信。
connection and how to debug them, so we are all set to go.
与所有以前的挑战一样，在本例中，该程序作为网络守护程序运行
on port 2994.
So we can use netcat to connect to this service which displays a final1 prompt.
But when we enter something we don’t see anything.
Mh.
另外，因为我们已经知道这将是一个格式字符串漏洞，我们可以尝试
to inject some characters such as %x, but again, nothing happens.
我们也可以尝试使用%s，因为如果您记得，它将以堆栈上的值作为地址
字符串的位置，因此，如果堆栈上的值未指向有效内存，则
program should crash, which would be another indication of a format string vulnerability.
But nope.
Also doesn’t do anything.
我们还可以尝试发送一个非常长的字符串，只是为了查看是否存在缓冲区溢出。
that would crash the program, but also doesn’t work.
您可以看到现在多次返回提示，这表示
程序总是读取有限数量的字符，而您一次发送了如此多的字符，
that the read loop was able to read many times.
So I guess it’s time to have a look at the source code.
Main calls two functions after setting up all the networking stuff.
The first one is getipport(), and the second one is parser().
Getipport calls the function getpeername(), so let’s see what that is about.
getpeername（）返回缓冲区中连接到socket sockfd的对等机的地址
pointed to by addr.
我们可以看到，它还定义了一个结构sockaddr_，其中显然将包含源代码
ip address and source port by the client that connected to the socket.
You can also look up how the struct exactly looks like on the man page for ip.
所以它基本上包含端口号和IP地址，IP地址是
a 32byte integer.
And sprintf will write this constructed string into hostname, which is a global variable.
Ok so once this function is complete, the code will call parser().
And parser will print the final1 prompt we already know.
Then it uses fgets to read 128 bytes into the line buffer.
然后它使用trim，它查找换行符或换行符的第一个匹配项
and replaces it with a 0.
Basically cutting the string at these positions.
Then it will check if the string you entered starts with “username”, or “login”.
Ahh, ok, so there are special commands for that prompt.
如果您输入用户名，它在后面会有一些额外的数据，因为它字符串会复制任何内容。
after the “username” part into the global variable username.
如果您要使用命令“login”，它将检查您是否指定了用户名
before, if not it tells you you follow a wrong protocol.
但是如果您之前指定了一个用户名，它将调用logit，并在字符串中插入一个指针。
after login, because it expects a password there.
密码不在logit中使用，它只是挑战的一个模型，但在那里
it uses a buffer and writes to it with snprintf.
基本上是为一个日志条目创建一行，这表示有一个登录尝试来自
a certain client for a specific user with a certain password.
And then this string logged in the system log.
Then this function returns and it will print “login failed”.
Armed with this knowledge we can try to use the prompt again.
And it does what we expect.
Now this failed login attempt should have been logged in the syslog.
So let’s check it out.
Note you have to be root to read that file.
所以tail，只获取/var/log/syslog的最后几行
在这里，从这个源IP和源端口的final1登录尝试，作为liveoverflow
with the password.
Okay.
但是格式字符串漏洞到底在哪里呢？
There is no printf where we controlled the format parameter.
为什么我这么匆忙？
我们还没有完全理解代码，是吗？
We read this code with certain assumptions without questioning if they are true.
The meaning of hacking, if anything, is about understanding computers on a deeper level.
但有一个功能让我们变得懒惰和被忽视，因为我们认为它确实如此
it’s job.
如果你从我创造的东西中拿走了任何东西，那就是，不要满足
with what you think you know, challenge your beliefs.
Ok, well that rant was a bit overplaying it.
But we did not look into this new function we encountered - syslog.
我想我要说的是，当你解决这些简单的挑战时，你达到了一个点
where you think you know every dangerous function, but that’s not true.
So don’t get lazy, and read the man page.
如果我们查看syslog的手册页，我们将看到第二个参数是一种格式
parameter.
syslog() generates a log message, which will be distributed by syslogd(8).
The priority argument is formed by ORing the facility and the level values (explained below).
其余参数是一种格式，如printf（3）中所示。
Syslog works like printf.
And buf in logit(), is the format parameter.
buf只包含我们输入的用户名和密码，因此我们可以注入
format characters.
Let’s try it.
Let’s login with %x stuff.
Login failed, check the syslog.
And there it is.
In brackets you can see the leaked values from the stack.
Perfect, now we have identified the bug.
从早期的格式字符串利用视频，我们了解到一个好的策略是覆盖
an address in the global offset table with another function, like system to execute commands.
Let’s think about what function would be convenient to overwrite.
I think, the strncmp is a cool function, because we control the first parameter.
The line.
And system uses the first parameter for the string to execute stuff.
因此，如果我们用系统替换strncmp，我们可以简单地键入一行并执行shell
command.
Ok, so let’s construct our exploit.
我们导入可能重要的内容，并像使用一样设置远程套接字连接
to.
And maybe we create a new function called, read_until.
Which is very useful in these kind of remote service challenges.
因此，read until应使用单个字符读取来填充缓冲区，直到缓冲区包含
the magic string specified by read_until.
And then we can simply write, read_until the final1 prompt.
And then we can do our stuff.
So first we specify a username.
读取到下一个提示，然后指定登录密码，然后再次读取直到下一个提示
prompt.
我使用的另一个技巧是函数raw_input（），它实际上是从用户那里读取输入。
in python, but is very convenient to kinda pause the script, until we hit enter.
所以当我们现在执行这个时，我们连接到服务，然后等待直到
enter in the script.
When we now check the running processes for final, we see two.
如果您记得，其中一个是父守护进程，而新的守护进程（具有更高的进程ID）
is the spawned child that is handling our client connection.
So we can attach gdb to that process and start collecting addresses of important symbols.
So first let’s figure out the address of strncmp in the global offset table.
With info functions and a search term we can find the function trampoline in the plt quickly.
我们可以把这些指令拆开，很快就能看到它跳到地址上。
stored here.
这指向全局偏移量表，显然包含实际地址
to strncmp in libc.
So that is our target address we want to overwrite.
Next is the address of system.
System is part of libc and we can quickly get the address of it here.
注意，通常libc是由于aslr而随机化的，但是在这个旧的linux系统上，或者
on embedded devices, it still works this way.
在一个真正的现代系统中，为了
calculate offsets and break ASLR.
Ok, so we have our target and we have the address that we want to write to it.
此外，生成的日志消息将包含源IP和端口，这可能会有所不同
in length.
Coming from localhost will be different than coming from a remote host.
So we should add this into our exploit to be reliable.
The challenge used getpeername to get the ip and port of it’s peer.
So we can use the equivalent to get your own name.
With getsockname().
Now we also know the source ip and port and can write code to adapt accordingly.
Also, I’m sorry, the code is really awful to read this way.
I don’t know why I never bothered to turn on syntax code highltighing.
So here we go.
Better late than never.
Syntax on.
Let’s have a look again at the logged line from earlier.
结尾处的这些字符看起来可疑地像ASCII，当我们转换它们时，我们会看到
that they spell “Login from… and so forth”.
Let’s do this again with some recognizable characters to find the username.
And there it is.
So it took roughly 14 pops of the stack to reach the username with the AAAA.
你可以看到A不完全对齐，它们甚至可能会移动，因为
of the length of the IP and port.
因此，第一步是通过调整
it will be a known aligned offset.
So in this case the hostname was 15 characters long.
And one more A would have filled up and alligned the memory.
So let’s think about what the shortest and longest hostname could be.
Shortest would be 9, longest 21.
Because we prefer multiples of four to be 32bit aligned, we decide to pad to 24 characters.
因此，我们取主机名的长度，从24减去它，然后我们知道有多少个A
we need.
Let’s try this again with some %x in the username.
Oh and we must not forget the newline at the end of our test inputs.
哦，不工作吗？
我们做错了什么？
Ahh… we forgot the username and login command.
仍然不起作用…
哦，行的长度只能是128字节，但是我们用这些%x中的28个发送更多…
See, so many small things that can go wrong and slow you down.
Now we get the login failed.
查看系统日志并搜索BS，我们看到……上帝啊，该死的……我们
forgot to add the padding with the As.
Ok, there we go... the Bs are now perfectly aligned.
Awesome.
Now it doesn’t matter what IP or port you have, it will always be exactly there.
And we can count the words on the stack and get the offset 17.
现在我们可以继续使用一个带有美元符号的%x来表示第17个
parameter, the 17th value on the stack.
例如，我们现在可以放置strncmp的全局偏移表条目的地址
here into the string, and then use %n to write to that address.
所以现在我们只需要知道填充有多大，我们需要写下
want.
If that confuses you, rewatch the old format string stuff.
所以在我们现在运行它之前，添加另一个原始输入，这样脚本就不会退出，然后
我们运行它，用gdb连接它，观察strncmp的got条目，然后看到
the login attempt it got overwritten.
Our goal is the lower part of the system address, which is 0xffb0.
So now we can calculate the correct number of characters we need to print.
And this is basically how the process now works.
我们用%n写信到地址，核对号码，计算丢失了多少或如何
太多了，我们超调，更正我们打印的字符数，重复直到我们
have constructed the full address for system.
这太烦人了，很烦人，需要一些时间，但一旦你得到了它，它
so cool.
So now I got the offsets right and the address is overwritten with the address of system.
现在我们可以将telnetlib技巧和interaction添加到我们的程序中，理论上来说
point all calls to strncm would call system instead.
如果您研究代码并考虑一下，只需在提示符上写一些东西
should result in command execution.
So let’s try it.
We get a prompt, and now we can type commands as if we were in a real shell.
程序读取我们的线路，调用strncmp，实际上它调用系统和
executes our commands.
同样，我们可以将漏洞复制到我们的Windows计算机上，将IP地址更改为
the VM and then get a remote shell.
令人惊叹的！